Kaomudie Mukhopadhyay

Data Analyst

http://www.linkedin.com/in/kaomudie-mukhopadhyay-33b1139b

+91-9315167142

https://github.com/kaomudiemukhopadhyay

I am a highly passionate individual who thrives upon seeking new challenges through my career majorly as a Data Analyst. I am an Insightful Senior Consultant with over 7 years of total experience in Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Incentive Compensation and Inside Sales. My initial years of working in the corporate industry push me to go further in discovering more things in it. Of course, I am motivated to join a group of seasoned and experienced Data Analysts/Scientists professionals in the industry respectively.

Experience

Data Analyst at NTT Data Business Solutions

March 2022 - April 2023

- Defined KPIs for sales, supply chain, defect analysis, and L2 support, driving data-guided strategies.
- · Utilized SQL, Python, and Excel for data tasks, ensuring accurate extraction, transformation, validation, data export/import.
- · Developed Power BI dashboards for interactive sales trends, market share, and inventory insights, aiding decisions.
- Conducted statistical analysis to enhance demand forecasts, improving predictive accuracy.
- · Applied basic Python coding for tasks, showcasing analytical skills.
- · Designed predictive model, reducing excess inventory costs by 15%, demonstrating problem-solving abilities.

Sales Analyst at Simplilearn

July 2021 - October 2021

- Team Monitoring, Daily reporting, Team management, Roster Management & Call Auditing o Acquiring New leads, Lead generation from various site, o Closing deals on real time
- · Price Negotiation for B2B Sales
- Extensively used Tools like CRM, Salesforce,3cx CRM

Unit head and Sales Champion at NoBroker Technology Pvt Ltd

June 2019 - May 2021

- · Proficient in both outbound and inbound sales operations within core team, leading monitoring, reporting, and roster management.
- · Demonstrated strong lead acquisition skills resulting in revenue growth; collaborated with benefits team to enhance processes.
- · Ensured precise payroll processing across cycles, managed compensation plans, and validated sales data.
- · Skilled in using tools like Kibana for data visualization, data export, and import, ensuring seamless operations.
- Effectively utilized tools including Slash RTC, CRM, and Salesforce for streamlined sales processes.

Senior Operational Analyst at Radical Minds Technologies PVT LTD

June 2017 - May 2019

- Held the position of Sales Operation & Quality Analyst at Goibibo Group PVT LTD & MakeMyTrip India PVT LTD, coaching agents for
 optimized performance, validating and refining business processes using RCA, QMS, BPMS methodologies, and collaborating with the
 operations team for process enhancement.
- Conducted quality calibration sessions, ensuring maintenance of standards and stepping in as a Back-Up Team Leader when required, while analyzing reports to identify process gaps, training needs, and resolving defaulted hotel bookings.
- Utilized Excel for precise data maintenance and visualization and harnessed data visualization tools for enhanced insights; collaborated
 effectively with the Ground team to resolve guest issues.

Sales Associate at Intelenet Global Services

December 2015 - June 2017

- Worked at Ge-SBI Credit card (B2B) division, sourcing potential new customers and maintaining regular contact with existing clients while effectively managing pre-sales, post-sales (upgrades), and escalations.
- Demonstrated strong negotiation skills by persuading potential customers, leading price negotiations, and achieving successful sales
 closures, while also proficiently handling and resolving escalations through both tickets and calls.

Tech Support at Sony India Pvt Ltd

September 2015 - December 2015

- Conducted troubleshooting for Vaio laptops and Bravia TVs, validating cases using various tools, while also resolving software-related issues by leveraging customer-provided troubleshooting data and addressing tickets through platforms like ServiceNow, JIRA, etc.
- · Managed critical issues with the support of the Global Command Center and provided timely status reports to higher authorities.

Skills

- · Data Visualization
- Data Analysis
- Salesforce CRM
- Advanced Excel
- SQL
- · Problem Solving
- PythonPower BI

· Leadership

- MS Excel
- Analytical and Research Skills
- Incentive Compensation Calculation
- Inside Sales

Education

- Bachelor of Technology in Automobile Engineering with 66% GPA NIMS University Jaipur, Rajasthan, 2015
- Higher secondary Education in Science with 75% GPA Dhanbad Public School- Dhanbad, Jharkhand, C.B.S.E, 2011
- Secondary Education in Science with 66% GPA DAV Public School, Koylanagar Dhanbad, Jharkhand, C.B.S.E, 2009

Certification

- Data Analysis Grow data Skills Present
- Google Data Analytics- Coursera- Sep 2022
- SQL for Data Analysis Udacity- July 2023
- Power Bi- Coursera- NOV 2022
- Microsoft excel from beginner to advanced- Udemy-June 2021
- SQL (Basics, Intermediate, Advanced) Hacker Rank July 2023
- Tata Data Visualization Forage -July 2023
- KPMG Data Analyst -Forage- Jun 2023
- Cisco Data Analytics Forage Jun 2023
- Accenture Data Analytics and Visualization Forage June 2023
- Salesforce Certified Associate Salesforce May 2023